Okay, I have something to show you that
goes with events. So, if you look at our
stacked HTML, ignore my terrible
styling. Don't use a center tag. I'm
just using it for this demonstration.
So, I have a div. Inside of that div, I
have another div. And inside of that
div, I have another div. Um, I've styled
them so you can see them on screen
visually. Each of them has an onclick
event. That onclick event calls this log
function, hello world. So, what would
you expect to happen if I click them?
Well, let's just click the outer one and
we'll see what happens. It logs hello
once, exactly like we would expect. What
happens when we click inside the second?
It also calls the same log function.
You'd probably expect it to just log
hello once as well. It logged it twice.
Odd. Well, let's click three layers in.
It logged it three times. Well, why is
that? Well, because technically when we
click on this div, we are clicking on
it. But because it's inside of this div,
we're also technically clicking on that
div. And because it's inside of this
outer div, we're technically clicking on
that. And because this is inside of the
HTML body, we're technically clicking on
that. So when we click here, all of
these were technically clicked on. And
handling how that event is processed is
an important part of JavaScript.